<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/</link><description>Recent content on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WFH Day 365</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/03/day365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/03/day365/</guid><description>WFH Day 365 I took some time during the weekend to minimize my belongings. What does that mean? I got rid of some redundant electronics in the Garage. I threw out some old clothes that clogged my closet. I organized my 3D Printer setup and reduced duplicate tools, and put the wanted stuff in some boxes to keep some order. I trashed some boxes with stuff that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember made it during the move&amp;hellip; There is so much more to minimize.</description></item><item><title>Day353</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/03/day353/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/03/day353/</guid><description>WFH Day 353 I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep too bad last night. I got up at around 7:15 am, made myself a coffee, and continued to read my current book Gerta. I&amp;rsquo;m a slow reader, and if I don&amp;rsquo;t put time aside for reading, I will never finish any longer book in a finite amount of time. Reading in bed at night is something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. I usually fall asleep pretty quickly, and then my Kindle, or even worse, my iPad, falls to my face.</description></item><item><title>Day350</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day350/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day350/</guid><description>WFH Day 350 It&amp;rsquo;s already the last day of a perfect month. Perfect in that sense that the month started with a Monday and ended adequately on a Sunday. :-)
I mentioned in my post that I was about to create my sourdough starter. It was an experiment, and I failed it. I assume that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the right place in my house with sufficient constant temperature (this house is so badly insulated :-|).</description></item><item><title>Day340</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day340/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day340/</guid><description>WFH Day 340 During my lunch break, I took a walk and visited my friends who own a coffee shop in our town. Yesterday, they told me that they would get their vaccination today. I was amazed to hear that since my healthcare provider is sending me weekly updates about the actual vaccination progress and that they vaccinate people over 75. It looks like I still have to wait a bit longer since they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough vaccines for this age group.</description></item><item><title>Day329</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day329/</guid><description>WFH Day 329 A new year, and still, we are mostly trapped and confined in our homes without much todo. The days seem to follow the same pattern day in, day out. I went back to exercise more, not to feel brain tired, and have something accomplished with my body.
Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s not what I wanted to write. It was only something that came to my mind before I come to what I started two days ago: making a Sourdough starter.</description></item><item><title>Day310</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/01/day310/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/01/day310/</guid><description>WFH Day 310 I&amp;rsquo;m currently in Germany visiting my family. The Lockdown is strict, and just the essential stores are open. The infections are still pretty high, and the government talks about more restrictions to bring down the numbers. It feels that there is nothing I can do more at this point. I stay and work from home. I go outside for a walk around the lake and get some groceries.</description></item><item><title>Advent Of Code 2020</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/advent-of-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/advent-of-code/</guid><description>Ho Ho Ho Now that we approach the last month of this extraordinary year, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to some coding challenges to distract myself and learn something new. And here it comes AdventOfCode. Sign in with any of the social accounts mentioned on their page and start solving the daily puzzles. The programming language doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. You can produce the solution with whatever language/tool you like. And don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check AdventOfCode Subreddit for hints, help, and the solutions others have produced.</description></item><item><title>Day240</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day240/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day240/</guid><description>WFH Day 240 After some time off last week, I&amp;rsquo;m finally back to work. I felt mentally exhausted and tired to the point of not having any motivation to do anything despite reading, hanging around, and sleeping. I made silly mistakes during the last minute changes that my teammates had to fix while I was gone. And to be honest, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a great feeling.
I feel better now, and I have more energy to tackle some of the more challenging work problems.</description></item><item><title>Day218</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day218/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day218/</guid><description>WFH Day 218 Today was the day! Adobe MAX arrived, and all the work of the previous months could be seen by everybody interested in our products. What a fantastic achievement in these crazy times.
I&amp;rsquo;m still fighting with a couple of things.
my 3D Printer drives me crazy (filament clogged the extruder, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the Teflon tube I needed to replace) working on some authentication-related issues for the CSDK, and it moves slow and brought up some obstacles along the way that makes the implementation more expensive.</description></item><item><title>Day205</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day205/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day205/</guid><description>WFH Day 205 I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on some very tricky programming issues at work. Things are moving slowly, and there are times when I think what the hell am I doing here. Luckily, this is a temporary state and will only get worse by working on something entirely different. Right, working on the leetcode October challenge can show me that things can get worse. Last night I spent 3 hours! On a simple (in retrospect, it was a straightforward) problem.</description></item><item><title>Day200</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day200/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day200/</guid><description>WFH Day 200 Time to celebrate 🎆
200 days WFH and mostly isolated and not entirely insane ;-)
Who would have guessed that it will last that long? And there is no end in sight
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at something tiny through a Macro Lens. Should we? Just to distract ourselves
Shot on Canon 6D with a 90mm Tamron Macro Lens
Red and Small</description></item><item><title>Day197</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day197/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day197/</guid><description>WFH Day 197 We are getting close to the 200-day mark for work at home. Not necessarily something to celebrate, but a noticeable milestone during these times and a sign that every prediction how long this situation is supposed to last was wrong. Only a couple of weeks left before the election, and tonight is the first debate between both presidential candidates. To protect my sanity, I&amp;rsquo;ll watch the debate only for 15 mins max.</description></item><item><title>Day192</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day192/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day192/</guid><description>WFH Day 192 We are approaching the final days of our Sprint. The majority of our clients are happy and don&amp;rsquo;t have significant functionality issues that would require our team to do some fire fighting. I was able to finish one last-minute task for a hotfix and another task for this release. In addition to finalizing both tasks, I was able to review some PRs and provide some feedback. I feel pretty accomplished today, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>Day189</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day189/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day189/</guid><description>WFH Day 189 Today was a &amp;ldquo;Terrible, Horrible, No Good, Very Bad Day&amp;rdquo;. I tried to make the best out of it. No luck. I woke up feeling like a truck rolled over my body. I pushed through the day and went for a run in the evening. Tomorrow is a new day. Looking forward to a fresh start.
Choose One Date: July 17, 2019 Aperture: 1.</description></item><item><title>Day186</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day186/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day186/</guid><description>WFH Day 186 Today was a great day! You may ask why it was a great day. Let me tell you that my employer is giving us a day off. On Fridays. Every three weeks. Until the end of the year! If this is not great, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to spark some fun. At least for the moment. I don&amp;rsquo;t know when it was the last time that I needed an additional day to recover.</description></item><item><title>Day184</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day184/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day184/</guid><description>WFH Day 184 What a day. A lot of meetings in the morning. After I finished all of them right before the lunch break, I found Beat Burnout And Zoom Fatigue: 3 Ways To Fight Stress And Stay Motivated During Coronavirus in my news feed today. Although I consider myself mindful and remind myself to take breaks during the day, exercise my aching body, I still sometimes feel tired and not motivated to my full extent.</description></item><item><title>Day183</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day183/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day183/</guid><description>WFH Day 183 How many T-shirts do I need? I did laundry today and was folding up my stuff. I was looking in my closet and found at least 20 T-Shirts and the additional pile of 15 T-shirts freshly laundered. I need to get rid of some of them. There is so much stuff in my life that it distracts me from more important things. I have this pile of desk supplies lying on the ground next to my desk.</description></item><item><title>Day182</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day182/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day182/</guid><description>WFH Day 182 That is a looong time that we are now hanging out at home. We won&amp;rsquo;t go back to the office anytime soon. So, we are stuck inside our homes for much longer. And because of the horrible air quality I can&amp;rsquo;t even go outside and exercise. It seems that this year brings all the catastrophes (pandemic, global warming, extreme heat and wildfires) in one go. This is usual material that science fictions stories are made of.</description></item><item><title>Day178</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day178/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day178/</guid><description>WFH Day 178 In addition to work from home we got really bad air quality. We didn&amp;rsquo;t see the sun since yesterdays orange tint. Today was not as bad as yesterday, but still no sun and it was gloomy as hell. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you any energy boost to get through the day. And don&amp;rsquo;t think about outside exercise. Trying to do something healthy gets in the way with the outside conditions.</description></item><item><title>Day26</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day26/</guid><description>WFH Day #26 Photo by Viktor Nikolaienko on Unsplash unsplash-logoViktor Nikolaienko</description></item><item><title>Design for Coffee Ground Distribution Tool Base with OpenSCAD</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/design-a-coffee-ground-distribution-base/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 17:40:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/design-a-coffee-ground-distribution-base/</guid><description>TL;DR A friend of mine asked me if I could build something useful with my 3D Printer. He wanted to have something to place his new (and expensive) tamper for ground coffee. I always wanted to design and print something useful on my 3D Printer. And I wanted to learn and use OpenSCAD for a long time. Now I had an excellent reason to learn it.
Create the Design I had no experience with OpenSCAD at all when I started this little project.</description></item><item><title>Day1</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day1/</guid><description>WFH Day 001 Today we got the notification from Adobe that we will close all the offices for all employees in north America. We were told to work from home for the next 30 days. After that period the situation will be evaluated and further decisions will be communicated by then. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what is going to happen.</description></item><item><title>Learning Crystal With Genetic Algorithms</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/learning-crystal-with-genetic-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 23:12:52 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/learning-crystal-with-genetic-algorithms/</guid><description>I like to learn new tools, programming languages, and exciting topics. I recently found the book Genetic Algorithms in Java Basics , and I found the code samples easy enough to understand to &amp;ldquo;translate&amp;rdquo; them to a different programming language for the sole purpose of getting some hands-on experience with a new programming language. I&amp;rsquo;m done with the 2nd chapter of the book and implemented the genetic algorithm described in that chapter to crystal lang.</description></item><item><title>Testing raw DOM Event Handler in Reactjs</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/testing-dom-event-handler-in-reactjs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 16:38:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/testing-dom-event-handler-in-reactjs/</guid><description>This is a reminder to myself. And to anybody who needs a creative solution to test an event handler directly attached to a DOM node of a react component.
Last Friday I ran into the situation to test my react component to ensure that the state updates correctly when the pointerenter and pointerleave event fires. Testing for these events is usually no big deal when you use reactjs in one way or the other (either web or native).</description></item><item><title>ReactJS San Francisco Meetup at Zendesk</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs_meetup_zendesk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:15:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs_meetup_zendesk/</guid><description>ReactJS San Francisco Meetup at Zendesk Thursday night I attended the SF ReactJS Meetup at Zendesk.
First of all, there were some noticeable difference to some other meetups I went to in the past,
No need to sign No need to sign an NDA before entering the premise No Pizza! The office space is gorgeous. Grass on the wall, stairs to sit on and a small atrium like opening from the basement to the first floor to bring some light to the lower level.</description></item><item><title>Resize APFS Container in macOS 10.13 VMWare Image</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-resize-apfs-container-in-macos-10.13-vmware-image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 22:45:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-resize-apfs-container-in-macos-10.13-vmware-image/</guid><description>Resize VMWare Disk size VMWare provides an option to resize the Hard disk of a VM. The Settings dialog provides this option under Hard Disk. If the VM is not running and you don&amp;rsquo;t have a snapshot, the slider is enabled, and you can size the disk to your desired size.
I wanted to increase the size of the hard disk from 50 GB to 100 GB. That&amp;rsquo;s a matter of seconds, and I was ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Effective Git - Worktrees</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/effective-git-worktrees/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 21:19:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/effective-git-worktrees/</guid><description>You know this situation: you are working on new feature branch of your product. A bunch of files has been changed, nothing has settled yet and lots of uncommitted changes. This is how work in progress looks like. Everything could be alright, but then you are asked to check out that high priority issue that a customer reported.
What I did in this situation
stash my changes with git stash save and provide a meaningful message for when I have to unstash- my changes changes branches and pull from master build the product repro the issue create a new branch for the fix implement the fix and push to the newly created branch let somebody else verify the fix go back to my previous branch git stash pop my work in progress continue working on the feature Introducing Worktrees I was reading git release notes, and I stumbled upon something I haven’t heard before in the git context: worktree.</description></item><item><title>Efficient JavaScript Unit Testing with Jest and Snapshots</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/efficient-unit-testing-with-jest-and-snapshots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 11:55:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/efficient-unit-testing-with-jest-and-snapshots/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a bold statement:
We all love to write unit great tests for our code. More or less.
— Unknown Programmer
Writing unit tests for my code mostly follows this pattern
Write a test and make it fail (red) Write the function to fix the test (implement function) Start over with step 1 For one of my projects, I was using jest. It&amp;rsquo;s fast now, and it has several features that I highly value.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 09/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-09/_index09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-09/_index09/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 09/2017 Howdy New York February 2005. I arrived in New York for a weekend stop over on the way to San Francisco. I wanted to visit the The Gates in Central Park.
I was hoping for some snow during the night and some sun for Saturday morning. I wanted to capture the glowing orange fabric surrounded by the bright white environment. When I woke up Saturday morning, I was surprised to see that both wishes had come true.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 08/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-08/_index08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-08/_index08/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 08/2017 Howdy I spent last Weekend in Yosemite, CA. It was a birthday present that my wife gave me. No children, away from home and time to attend a photography class in Yosemite. The class was organized from the Ansel Adams Gallery.
The class was 4 hours long and I took a lot of shots during the class. It was a lot of experimentation with the camera. How to deal with over-exposure, composition, color, white balancing, experiments with aperture priority, etc.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 07/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-07/_index07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-07/_index07/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 07/2017 Howdy I spent last Tuesday in San Jose, CA at the bi-annual Adobe developer conference that took place in the San Jose Convention Center. The evening of the second day usually ends with the TechFair. Teams are showing off what they are working on. That&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting part of the whole conference. You get some ideas about what is going on in the company and where we are heading.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 06/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-06/_index06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-06/_index06/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 06/2017 Happy Monday!
About the Image Last Sunday I was spending some time walking around the football field at our middle school. The weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t that great. Grey and cloudy skies and lots of gusty winds. Then my little daughter showed up with some daisies she has picked from the field. It looked so fragile, how she was holding the tiny flowers in her little hands. Squeezed between her little fingers.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 05/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-05/_index05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-05/_index05/</guid><description>Happy Monday!
About the Image As you can see: I love Santa Cruz!. This photo was taken on 02/14/2016. I spent the long weekend with my family in Santa Cruz. We stayed close to that beautiful beach and spent the afternoon in the sun.
The image was taken with a Sony Alpha A7II and the 28-70 mm Lens (53mm, f/9, 1⁄250, ISO 100).
I used Lightroom to crop the image a little bit.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 04/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-04/_index04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-04/_index04/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 04/2017 About the Image Happy Monday!
This week, I have again a photo from Santa Cruz, CA. I’ve taken this photo on 01/15/2017, during my Sunday trip to the beach. The image was taken with a Sony Alpha A7II and the 28-70 mm Lens (70mm, f/9, 1⁄200, ISO 100).
The photo was slightly rotated to have straight vertical lines. I used the Lightroom Blue Hi-Contrast Filter for B/W conversion.</description></item><item><title>My Wallpaper Photo of the Week</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/my-wallpaper-photo-of-the-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 23:30:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/my-wallpaper-photo-of-the-week/</guid><description>My Wallpaper Photo of the Week Every Monday, I&amp;rsquo;ll post the photo, that will be my Desktop background for one week. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a description of the subject, where it was taken and what the camera settings were (if I remember them). All photos will be taken by myself. I&amp;rsquo;ll release them in the highest availble quality. If you like a photo, you can download it for your personal use. Each photo contains a watermark with my name and year.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 03</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-03/_index03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-03/_index03/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 03/2017 About the Image The image was taken on my iPhone 7 Plus with Microsoft Pix. Finishing touches with Adobe Lightroom 6.8. Sunset in Santa Cruz last Sunday (01/15/2017)
Thanks for reading! 📷</description></item><item><title>Get Up And Start Walking</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/get-up-and-start-walking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 11:55:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/get-up-and-start-walking/</guid><description>&amp;#34;&amp;#34; If you want something you never had, then do something you never did. &amp;#34;&amp;#34; — Nossrat Peseschkian When I heard the above quote for the first time, it was eye opening to me. Why? It expresses very clearly to me, that you need to get active, if you want to reach a goal in your life. No matter what it is. Get a promotion, earn more money, hike the Pacific Crest Trail.</description></item><item><title>TIL - SIGINFO is awesome</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-siginfo-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 09:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-siginfo-is-awesome/</guid><description>Today I learnt something really awesome. If you use a Unix based operating system, then you will be able to send any process a signal. This might be either Ctrl+C or SIGINT to interrupt that process. Or you can send SIGINFO to report the progress of it’s operation. Why this is awesome? Did you ever copy a huge amount of data and cp didn’t tell you how much has data has been copied so far?</description></item><item><title>Don't say it. Do it!</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/dont-say-it-do-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 23:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/dont-say-it-do-it/</guid><description> Don’t talk too much about the things you want to do.
Don’t overthink everything.
Don’t make it more complicated than it has to be.
Don’t stop learning.
Don’t stop trying.
Try harder.
Try smarter.
Don’t say “it’s impossible”.
Move faster.
Do it!</description></item><item><title>TIL - Reactjs optimization that cost me some time</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs-optimizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 23:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs-optimizations/</guid><description>I was building a Reactjs component, that should toggle between two child components.
&amp;lt;Toggle&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Comp1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Comp2&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Toggle&amp;gt; The render method of Toggle looked like this
render() { const content = React.Children.count(this.props.children) &amp;gt; 0 ? this.props.children[0] : this.props.children[1]; return ( ${content} ); } Unfortunately, this didn’t work (index out of bounds), when I passed only one component instead of two. This doesn’t make sense since the Toggle is supposed to toggle between two components.</description></item><item><title>TIL - where to put ant-contrib</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-where-to-put-ant-contrib/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 20:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-where-to-put-ant-contrib/</guid><description>I was testing an ant based build script change today. And I thought ant was already retired.
Running the script led to a lot of warnings about a missing library. I asked the person, if there are any dependencies for ant-contrib. His response was &amp;#34;yes, you need to install ant-contrib&amp;#34;.
First of all, I didn’t have ant installed. But that was easy with
irichter@irichter-MacBookPro:~ brew install ant Unfortunately, ant-contrib wasn’t available via homebrew, so I had to download it and place it…​ where?</description></item><item><title>Welcome to my new blog presence</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 18:49:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</guid><description>After a long time, I’m finally moving my blog to this new github hosted location. Cleaner setup, easier to maintain and independent from any content management system.
This will be home to all new posts in the future. There will be tweaks to the setup and layout in the next couple of days. It’s not perfect yet, but I wanted to get it going. The blog will be available under this domain.</description></item></channel></rss>