<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 23:12:52 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning Crystal With Genetic Algorithms</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/learning-crystal-with-genetic-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 23:12:52 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/learning-crystal-with-genetic-algorithms/</guid><description>I like to learn new tools, programming languages, and exciting topics. I recently found the book Genetic Algorithms in Java Basics , and I found the code samples easy enough to understand to &amp;ldquo;translate&amp;rdquo; them to a different programming language for the sole purpose of getting some hands-on experience with a new programming language. I&amp;rsquo;m done with the 2nd chapter of the book and implemented the genetic algorithm described in that chapter to crystal lang.</description></item><item><title>Effective Git - Worktrees</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/effective-git-worktrees/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 21:19:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/effective-git-worktrees/</guid><description>You know this situation: you are working on new feature branch of your product. A bunch of files has been changed, nothing has settled yet and lots of uncommitted changes. This is how work in progress looks like. Everything could be alright, but then you are asked to check out that high priority issue that a customer reported.
What I did in this situation
stash my changes with git stash save and provide a meaningful message for when I have to unstash- my changes changes branches and pull from master build the product repro the issue create a new branch for the fix implement the fix and push to the newly created branch let somebody else verify the fix go back to my previous branch git stash pop my work in progress continue working on the feature Introducing Worktrees I was reading git release notes, and I stumbled upon something I haven’t heard before in the git context: worktree.</description></item><item><title>Efficient JavaScript Unit Testing with Jest and Snapshots</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/efficient-unit-testing-with-jest-and-snapshots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 11:55:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/efficient-unit-testing-with-jest-and-snapshots/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a bold statement:
We all love to write unit great tests for our code. More or less.
— Unknown Programmer
Writing unit tests for my code mostly follows this pattern
Write a test and make it fail (red) Write the function to fix the test (implement function) Start over with step 1 For one of my projects, I was using jest. It&amp;rsquo;s fast now, and it has several features that I highly value.</description></item><item><title>TIL - Reactjs optimization that cost me some time</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs-optimizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 23:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs-optimizations/</guid><description>I was building a Reactjs component, that should toggle between two child components.
&amp;lt;Toggle&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Comp1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Comp2&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Toggle&amp;gt; The render method of Toggle looked like this
render() { const content = React.Children.count(this.props.children) &amp;gt; 0 ? this.props.children[0] : this.props.children[1]; return ( ${content} ); } Unfortunately, this didn’t work (index out of bounds), when I passed only one component instead of two. This doesn’t make sense since the Toggle is supposed to toggle between two components.</description></item><item><title>TIL - where to put ant-contrib</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-where-to-put-ant-contrib/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 20:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-where-to-put-ant-contrib/</guid><description>I was testing an ant based build script change today. And I thought ant was already retired.
Running the script led to a lot of warnings about a missing library. I asked the person, if there are any dependencies for ant-contrib. His response was &amp;#34;yes, you need to install ant-contrib&amp;#34;.
First of all, I didn’t have ant installed. But that was easy with
irichter@irichter-MacBookPro:~ brew install ant Unfortunately, ant-contrib wasn’t available via homebrew, so I had to download it and place it…​ where?</description></item></channel></rss>