<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3DPrinting on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/categories/3dprinting/</link><description>Recent content in 3DPrinting on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</managingEditor><webMaster>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/categories/3dprinting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Update Prusa Mk3s Fan Shroud</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/update-prusa-mk3s-fan-shroud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/update-prusa-mk3s-fan-shroud/</guid><description>A Better Fan Shroud I already updated my 3D Printer fan shroud a couple of months ago. It should cool the filament more effectively and evenly. I think it did a good job. Unfortunately, the shroud got too hot several times and was deformed. I was afraid that it now had reduced cooling performance. I found an update to the fan shroud that looked very efficient, and somebody analyzed the airflow, and it appeared to be very effective in cooling the filament.</description></item><item><title>3d Printed Axidraw Easel Spacer</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/3d-printed-axidraw-easel-spacer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/3d-printed-axidraw-easel-spacer/</guid><description>Designing a Spacer for my AxiDraw Plotter I have an AxiDraw V3/A3 Penplotter that I bought to satisfy a desire to own such a fantastic machine. It started in my teen years working with HP Plotters in our university lab at the TUHH. I could not afford an HP Plotter back in the day, so that desire was never satisfied.
Jumping forward to today: I bought the AxiDraw Plotter in the Summer of 2021, and I ordered the Magnetic Easel.</description></item><item><title>Design for Coffee Ground Distribution Tool Base with OpenSCAD</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/design-a-coffee-ground-distribution-base/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 17:40:42 -0700</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/design-a-coffee-ground-distribution-base/</guid><description>TL;DR A friend of mine asked me if I could build something useful with my 3D Printer. He wanted to have something to place his new (and expensive) tamper for ground coffee. I always wanted to design and print something useful on my 3D Printer. And I wanted to learn and use OpenSCAD for a long time. Now I had an excellent reason to learn it.
Create the Design I had no experience with OpenSCAD at all when I started this little project.</description></item></channel></rss>