<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wallpaper on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/tags/wallpaper/</link><description>Recent content in Wallpaper on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</managingEditor><webMaster>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/tags/wallpaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 09/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-09/_index09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-09/_index09/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 09/2017 Howdy New York February 2005. I arrived in New York for a weekend stop over on the way to San Francisco. I wanted to visit the The Gates in Central Park.
I was hoping for some snow during the night and some sun for Saturday morning. I wanted to capture the glowing orange fabric surrounded by the bright white environment. When I woke up Saturday morning, I was surprised to see that both wishes had come true.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 08/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-08/_index08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-08/_index08/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 08/2017 Howdy I spent last Weekend in Yosemite, CA. It was a birthday present that my wife gave me. No children, away from home and time to attend a photography class in Yosemite. The class was organized from the Ansel Adams Gallery.
The class was 4 hours long and I took a lot of shots during the class. It was a lot of experimentation with the camera. How to deal with over-exposure, composition, color, white balancing, experiments with aperture priority, etc.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 07/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-07/_index07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-07/_index07/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 07/2017 Howdy I spent last Tuesday in San Jose, CA at the bi-annual Adobe developer conference that took place in the San Jose Convention Center. The evening of the second day usually ends with the TechFair. Teams are showing off what they are working on. That&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting part of the whole conference. You get some ideas about what is going on in the company and where we are heading.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 06/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-06/_index06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-06/_index06/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 06/2017 Happy Monday!
About the Image Last Sunday I was spending some time walking around the football field at our middle school. The weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t that great. Grey and cloudy skies and lots of gusty winds. Then my little daughter showed up with some daisies she has picked from the field. It looked so fragile, how she was holding the tiny flowers in her little hands. Squeezed between her little fingers.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 05/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-05/_index05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-05/_index05/</guid><description>Happy Monday!
About the Image As you can see: I love Santa Cruz!. This photo was taken on 02/14/2016. I spent the long weekend with my family in Santa Cruz. We stayed close to that beautiful beach and spent the afternoon in the sun.
The image was taken with a Sony Alpha A7II and the 28-70 mm Lens (53mm, f/9, 1⁄250, ISO 100).
I used Lightroom to crop the image a little bit.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 04/2017</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-04/_index04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-04/_index04/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 04/2017 About the Image Happy Monday!
This week, I have again a photo from Santa Cruz, CA. I’ve taken this photo on 01/15/2017, during my Sunday trip to the beach. The image was taken with a Sony Alpha A7II and the 28-70 mm Lens (70mm, f/9, 1⁄200, ISO 100).
The photo was slightly rotated to have straight vertical lines. I used the Lightroom Blue Hi-Contrast Filter for B/W conversion.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Wallpaper Week 03</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-03/_index03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/wallpaper/2017/week-03/_index03/</guid><description>Wallpaper Week 03/2017 About the Image The image was taken on my iPhone 7 Plus with Microsoft Pix. Finishing touches with Adobe Lightroom 6.8. Sunset in Santa Cruz last Sunday (01/15/2017)
Thanks for reading! 📷</description></item></channel></rss>