<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Post on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Post on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Friday Evening Source Code Changes</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/friday-evening-source-code-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/friday-evening-source-code-changes/</guid><description>Well, Crap, what a waste of time One would guess that I should have known better with the work experience I accumulated in the software engineering field.
But, it&amp;rsquo;s Friday evening, after our social team meeting, and I am still excited to finish something substantial for this feature that I&amp;rsquo;m working. Lots of moving parts, refactored code, loose ends, and hastily glued together code without any safety net. A couple of new unit tests for the new feature and some legacy code that I have to touch.</description></item><item><title>3d Printed Axidraw Easel Spacer</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/3d-printed-axidraw-easel-spacer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/3d-printed-axidraw-easel-spacer/</guid><description>Designing a Spacer for my AxiDraw Plotter I have an AxiDraw V3/A3 Penplotter that I bought to satisfy a desire to own such a fantastic machine. It started in my teen years working with HP Plotters in our university lab at the TUHH. I could not afford an HP Plotter back in the day, so that desire was never satisfied.
Jumping forward to today: I bought the AxiDraw Plotter in the Summer of 2021, and I ordered the Magnetic Easel.</description></item><item><title>TIL - Adding Swift Code to Objective-C Project</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/til-adding-swift-code-to-objective-c-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/til-adding-swift-code-to-objective-c-project/</guid><description>TL;DR Adding Swift Code to Objective-C Project
Ensure your Swift class derives direct or indirect from NSObject Ensure your Swift class is public to ensure the YourProjectName-Swift.h header generation Prefix the class to expose it to Objective-C. Any Property or method needs its own @objc annotation to be visible from Objective-C. Use the @objcMembers annotation to expose all properties and methods of the Swift class Reminder for myself I learned a couple of essential things about mixing Objective-C and Swift in one project.</description></item><item><title>Adding Multiple Files to Macos Gatekeeper</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/adding-multiple-files-to-macos-gatekeeper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/adding-multiple-files-to-macos-gatekeeper/</guid><description>The Gatekeeper Before I forget what I learned today, I better write it down.
Gatekeeper on macOS ensures that properly signed and authentic apps and other executable files, including dylibs and kexts, are executed on your Mac. But if you want to execute an open-source tool installed by brew or some other way on your machine, you will usually see something like this confirmation dialog. In this case, for an app FSNotes installed with brew.</description></item><item><title>Hugo, Themes and My Theme Customization</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/hugo-themes-and-my-theme-customization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/hugo-themes-and-my-theme-customization/</guid><description>TL;DR Hugo&amp;rsquo;s file lookup magic was biting me and was causing the 3rd party template to use a file with the same name from my blog assets directory.
How to waste lots of hours I use Hugo for my Blog with a custom theme hugo future imperfect slim.
I made some customizations to my blog a while ago. I added baguetteBox.js for better image galleries and lazySizes to better support different image sizes in the gallery.</description></item><item><title>Swiftui Learn by Doing</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/swiftui---learn-by-doing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/swiftui---learn-by-doing/</guid><description>SwiftUI - Learn by doing I briefly started to use SwiftUI in 2021. I wanted to learn about the fundamentals and how SwiftUI differs from the traditional iOS and macOS development frameworks.
Over the next couple of weeks, I will provide tutorials to help others learn SwiftUI by building some apps. I&amp;rsquo;m going to start building a Minesweeper clone. Minesweeper is a simple game that I loved to play when it was released with Windows 3.</description></item><item><title>Happy Thanksgiving 🦃</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2021/happy-thanksgiving/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2021/happy-thanksgiving/</guid><description>Happy Thanksgiving I wish everybody a great day with their families and friends. I hope you can all meet in person and make up for last year. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for having a family and friends, a roof over my head, and a fulfilling job.
Happy Turkey Day, or whatever suits your mood. Stay safe wherever you are and get some time for yourself.
Cheers 🥂</description></item><item><title>TIL - Organize a Folder of Thousands of Images Into Subfolders</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2021/organize-a-folder-of-thousands-of-images-into-subfolders/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2021/organize-a-folder-of-thousands-of-images-into-subfolders/</guid><description>Reorg Time I use Nextclouds image upload feature to backup all photos from my phone. I recently discovered that you could upload pictures from your phone into subfolders in the YEAR/MONTH/DAY/picturefile format.
After switching this feature on, I realized that all my previously uploaded 3000+ images and short videos lie flat in the Pictures folder. I needed a solution to organize all existing photos into the same subfolder structure.
I was thinking about writing a shell script and using ExifTool to read the EXIF metadata and move the pictures into their respective folder location based on their creation date.</description></item><item><title>Advent Of Code 2020</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/advent-of-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/advent-of-code/</guid><description>Ho Ho Ho Now that we approach the last month of this extraordinary year, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to some coding challenges to distract myself and learn something new. And here it comes AdventOfCode. Sign in with any of the social accounts mentioned on their page and start solving the daily puzzles. The programming language doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. You can produce the solution with whatever language/tool you like. And don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check AdventOfCode Subreddit for hints, help, and the solutions others have produced.</description></item><item><title>Design for Coffee Ground Distribution Tool Base with OpenSCAD</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/design-a-coffee-ground-distribution-base/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 17:40:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2020/design-a-coffee-ground-distribution-base/</guid><description>TL;DR A friend of mine asked me if I could build something useful with my 3D Printer. He wanted to have something to place his new (and expensive) tamper for ground coffee. I always wanted to design and print something useful on my 3D Printer. And I wanted to learn and use OpenSCAD for a long time. Now I had an excellent reason to learn it.
Create the Design I had no experience with OpenSCAD at all when I started this little project.</description></item><item><title>Learning Crystal With Genetic Algorithms</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/learning-crystal-with-genetic-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 23:12:52 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/learning-crystal-with-genetic-algorithms/</guid><description>I like to learn new tools, programming languages, and exciting topics. I recently found the book Genetic Algorithms in Java Basics , and I found the code samples easy enough to understand to &amp;ldquo;translate&amp;rdquo; them to a different programming language for the sole purpose of getting some hands-on experience with a new programming language. I&amp;rsquo;m done with the 2nd chapter of the book and implemented the genetic algorithm described in that chapter to crystal lang.</description></item><item><title>Testing raw DOM Event Handler in Reactjs</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/testing-dom-event-handler-in-reactjs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 16:38:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/testing-dom-event-handler-in-reactjs/</guid><description>This is a reminder to myself. And to anybody who needs a creative solution to test an event handler directly attached to a DOM node of a react component.
Last Friday I ran into the situation to test my react component to ensure that the state updates correctly when the pointerenter and pointerleave event fires. Testing for these events is usually no big deal when you use reactjs in one way or the other (either web or native).</description></item><item><title>ReactJS San Francisco Meetup at Zendesk</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs_meetup_zendesk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:15:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs_meetup_zendesk/</guid><description>ReactJS San Francisco Meetup at Zendesk Thursday night I attended the SF ReactJS Meetup at Zendesk.
First of all, there were some noticeable difference to some other meetups I went to in the past,
No need to sign No need to sign an NDA before entering the premise No Pizza! The office space is gorgeous. Grass on the wall, stairs to sit on and a small atrium like opening from the basement to the first floor to bring some light to the lower level.</description></item><item><title>Resize APFS Container in macOS 10.13 VMWare Image</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-resize-apfs-container-in-macos-10.13-vmware-image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 22:45:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-resize-apfs-container-in-macos-10.13-vmware-image/</guid><description>Resize VMWare Disk size VMWare provides an option to resize the Hard disk of a VM. The Settings dialog provides this option under Hard Disk. If the VM is not running and you don&amp;rsquo;t have a snapshot, the slider is enabled, and you can size the disk to your desired size.
I wanted to increase the size of the hard disk from 50 GB to 100 GB. That&amp;rsquo;s a matter of seconds, and I was ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Effective Git - Worktrees</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/effective-git---worktrees/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 21:19:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/effective-git---worktrees/</guid><description>You know this situation: you are working on new feature branch of your product. A bunch of files has been changed, nothing has settled yet and lots of uncommitted changes. This is how work in progress looks like. Everything could be alright, but then you are asked to check out that high priority issue that a customer reported.
What I did in this situation
stash my changes with git stash save and provide a meaningful message for when I have to unstash- my changes changes branches and pull from master build the product repro the issue create a new branch for the fix implement the fix and push to the newly created branch let somebody else verify the fix go back to my previous branch git stash pop my work in progress continue working on the feature Introducing Worktrees I was reading git release notes, and I stumbled upon something I haven’t heard before in the git context: worktree.</description></item><item><title>Efficient JavaScript Unit Testing with Jest and Snapshots</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/efficient-unit-testing-with-jest-and-snapshots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 11:55:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/efficient-unit-testing-with-jest-and-snapshots/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a bold statement:
We all love to write unit great tests for our code. More or less.
— Unknown Programmer
Writing unit tests for my code mostly follows this pattern
Write a test and make it fail (red) Write the function to fix the test (implement function) Start over with step 1 For one of my projects, I was using jest. It&amp;rsquo;s fast now, and it has several features that I highly value.</description></item><item><title>My Wallpaper Photo of the Week</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/my-wallpaper-photo-of-the-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 23:30:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/my-wallpaper-photo-of-the-week/</guid><description>My Wallpaper Photo of the Week Every Monday, I&amp;rsquo;ll post the photo, that will be my Desktop background for one week. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a description of the subject, where it was taken and what the camera settings were (if I remember them). All photos will be taken by myself. I&amp;rsquo;ll release them in the highest availble quality. If you like a photo, you can download it for your personal use. Each photo contains a watermark with my name and year.</description></item><item><title>Get Up And Start Walking</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/get-up-and-start-walking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 11:55:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/get-up-and-start-walking/</guid><description>&amp;#34;&amp;#34; If you want something you never had, then do something you never did. &amp;#34;&amp;#34; — Nossrat Peseschkian When I heard the above quote for the first time, it was eye opening to me. Why? It expresses very clearly to me, that you need to get active, if you want to reach a goal in your life. No matter what it is. Get a promotion, earn more money, hike the Pacific Crest Trail.</description></item><item><title>TIL - SIGINFO is awesome</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-siginfo-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 09:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-siginfo-is-awesome/</guid><description>Today I learnt something really awesome. If you use a Unix based operating system, then you will be able to send any process a signal. This might be either Ctrl+C or SIGINT to interrupt that process. Or you can send SIGINFO to report the progress of it’s operation. Why this is awesome? Did you ever copy a huge amount of data and cp didn’t tell you how much has data has been copied so far?</description></item><item><title>Don't say it. Do it!</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/dont-say-it-do-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 23:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/dont-say-it-do-it/</guid><description>Don’t talk too much about the things you want to do.
Don’t overthink everything.
Don’t make it more complicated than it has to be.
Don’t stop learning.
Don’t stop trying.
Try harder.
Try smarter.
Don’t say “it’s impossible”.
Move faster.
Do it!</description></item><item><title>TIL - Reactjs optimization that cost me some time</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs-optimizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 23:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs-optimizations/</guid><description>I was building a Reactjs component, that should toggle between two child components.
&amp;lt;Toggle&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Comp1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Comp2&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Toggle&amp;gt; The render method of Toggle looked like this
render() { const content = React.Children.count(this.props.children) &amp;gt; 0 ? this.props.children[0] : this.props.children[1]; return ( ${content} ); } Unfortunately, this didn’t work (index out of bounds), when I passed only one component instead of two. This doesn’t make sense since the Toggle is supposed to toggle between two components.</description></item><item><title>TIL - where to put ant-contrib</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-where-to-put-ant-contrib/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 20:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-where-to-put-ant-contrib/</guid><description>I was testing an ant based build script change today. And I thought ant was already retired.
Running the script led to a lot of warnings about a missing library. I asked the person, if there are any dependencies for ant-contrib. His response was &amp;#34;yes, you need to install ant-contrib&amp;#34;.
First of all, I didn’t have ant installed. But that was easy with
irichter@irichter-MacBookPro:~ brew install ant Unfortunately, ant-contrib wasn’t available via homebrew, so I had to download it and place it…​ where?</description></item><item><title>Welcome to my new blog presence</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 18:49:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</guid><description>After a long time, I’m finally moving my blog to this new github hosted location. Cleaner setup, easier to maintain and independent from any content management system.
This will be home to all new posts in the future. There will be tweaks to the setup and layout in the next couple of days. It’s not perfect yet, but I wanted to get it going. The blog will be available under this domain.</description></item></channel></rss>