<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COVID19 on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/tags/covid19/</link><description>Recent content in COVID19 on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/tags/covid19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day329</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day329/</guid><description>WFH Day 329 A new year, and still, we are mostly trapped and confined in our homes without much todo. The days seem to follow the same pattern day in, day out. I went back to exercise more, not to feel brain tired, and have something accomplished with my body.
Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s not what I wanted to write. It was only something that came to my mind before I come to what I started two days ago: making a Sourdough starter.</description></item><item><title>Day310</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/01/day310/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/01/day310/</guid><description>WFH Day 310 I&amp;rsquo;m currently in Germany visiting my family. The Lockdown is strict, and just the essential stores are open. The infections are still pretty high, and the government talks about more restrictions to bring down the numbers. It feels that there is nothing I can do more at this point. I stay and work from home. I go outside for a walk around the lake and get some groceries.</description></item><item><title>Day240</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day240/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day240/</guid><description>WFH Day 240 After some time off last week, I&amp;rsquo;m finally back to work. I felt mentally exhausted and tired to the point of not having any motivation to do anything despite reading, hanging around, and sleeping. I made silly mistakes during the last minute changes that my teammates had to fix while I was gone. And to be honest, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a great feeling.
I feel better now, and I have more energy to tackle some of the more challenging work problems.</description></item><item><title>Day218</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day218/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day218/</guid><description>WFH Day 218 Today was the day! Adobe MAX arrived, and all the work of the previous months could be seen by everybody interested in our products. What a fantastic achievement in these crazy times.
I&amp;rsquo;m still fighting with a couple of things.
my 3D Printer drives me crazy (filament clogged the extruder, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the Teflon tube I needed to replace) working on some authentication-related issues for the CSDK, and it moves slow and brought up some obstacles along the way that makes the implementation more expensive.</description></item><item><title>Day205</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day205/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day205/</guid><description>WFH Day 205 I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on some very tricky programming issues at work. Things are moving slowly, and there are times when I think what the hell am I doing here. Luckily, this is a temporary state and will only get worse by working on something entirely different. Right, working on the leetcode October challenge can show me that things can get worse. Last night I spent 3 hours! On a simple (in retrospect, it was a straightforward) problem.</description></item><item><title>Day200</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day200/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day200/</guid><description>WFH Day 200 Time to celebrate 🎆
200 days WFH and mostly isolated and not entirely insane ;-)
Who would have guessed that it will last that long? And there is no end in sight
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at something tiny through a Macro Lens. Should we? Just to distract ourselves
Shot on Canon 6D with a 90mm Tamron Macro Lens
Red and Small</description></item><item><title>Day197</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day197/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day197/</guid><description>WFH Day 197 We are getting close to the 200-day mark for work at home. Not necessarily something to celebrate, but a noticeable milestone during these times and a sign that every prediction how long this situation is supposed to last was wrong. Only a couple of weeks left before the election, and tonight is the first debate between both presidential candidates. To protect my sanity, I&amp;rsquo;ll watch the debate only for 15 mins max.</description></item><item><title>Day192</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day192/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day192/</guid><description>WFH Day 192 We are approaching the final days of our Sprint. The majority of our clients are happy and don&amp;rsquo;t have significant functionality issues that would require our team to do some fire fighting. I was able to finish one last-minute task for a hotfix and another task for this release. In addition to finalizing both tasks, I was able to review some PRs and provide some feedback. I feel pretty accomplished today, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>Day189</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day189/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day189/</guid><description>WFH Day 189 Today was a &amp;ldquo;Terrible, Horrible, No Good, Very Bad Day&amp;rdquo;. I tried to make the best out of it. No luck. I woke up feeling like a truck rolled over my body. I pushed through the day and went for a run in the evening. Tomorrow is a new day. Looking forward to a fresh start.
Choose One Date: July 17, 2019 Aperture: 1.</description></item><item><title>Day186</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day186/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day186/</guid><description>WFH Day 186 Today was a great day! You may ask why it was a great day. Let me tell you that my employer is giving us a day off. On Fridays. Every three weeks. Until the end of the year! If this is not great, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to spark some fun. At least for the moment. I don&amp;rsquo;t know when it was the last time that I needed an additional day to recover.</description></item><item><title>Day184</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day184/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day184/</guid><description>WFH Day 184 What a day. A lot of meetings in the morning. After I finished all of them right before the lunch break, I found Beat Burnout And Zoom Fatigue: 3 Ways To Fight Stress And Stay Motivated During Coronavirus in my news feed today. Although I consider myself mindful and remind myself to take breaks during the day, exercise my aching body, I still sometimes feel tired and not motivated to my full extent.</description></item><item><title>Day183</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day183/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day183/</guid><description>WFH Day 183 How many T-shirts do I need? I did laundry today and was folding up my stuff. I was looking in my closet and found at least 20 T-Shirts and the additional pile of 15 T-shirts freshly laundered. I need to get rid of some of them. There is so much stuff in my life that it distracts me from more important things. I have this pile of desk supplies lying on the ground next to my desk.</description></item><item><title>Day182</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day182/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day182/</guid><description>WFH Day 182 That is a looong time that we are now hanging out at home. We won&amp;rsquo;t go back to the office anytime soon. So, we are stuck inside our homes for much longer. And because of the horrible air quality I can&amp;rsquo;t even go outside and exercise. It seems that this year brings all the catastrophes (pandemic, global warming, extreme heat and wildfires) in one go. This is usual material that science fictions stories are made of.</description></item><item><title>Day178</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day178/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day178/</guid><description>WFH Day 178 In addition to work from home we got really bad air quality. We didn&amp;rsquo;t see the sun since yesterdays orange tint. Today was not as bad as yesterday, but still no sun and it was gloomy as hell. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you any energy boost to get through the day. And don&amp;rsquo;t think about outside exercise. Trying to do something healthy gets in the way with the outside conditions.</description></item><item><title>Day26</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day26/</guid><description>WFH Day #26 Photo by Viktor Nikolaienko on Unsplash unsplash-logoViktor Nikolaienko</description></item><item><title>Day1</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2020/day1/</guid><description>WFH Day 001 Today we got the notification from Adobe that we will close all the offices for all employees in north America. we were told to work from home for the next 30 days. After that period the situation will be evaluated and further decisions will be communicated by then. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what is going to happen.</description></item></channel></rss>