<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:15:27 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ReactJS San Francisco Meetup at Zendesk</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs_meetup_zendesk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:15:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/reactjs_meetup_zendesk/</guid><description>ReactJS San Francisco Meetup at Zendesk Thursday night I attended the SF ReactJS Meetup at Zendesk.
First of all, there were some noticeable difference to some other meetups I went to in the past,
No need to sign No need to sign an NDA before entering the premise No Pizza! The office space is gorgeous. Grass on the wall, stairs to sit on and a small atrium like opening from the basement to the first floor to bring some light to the lower level.</description></item><item><title>Resize APFS Container in macOS 10.13 VMWare Image</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-resize-apfs-container-in-macos-10.13-vmware-image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 22:45:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-resize-apfs-container-in-macos-10.13-vmware-image/</guid><description>Resize VMWare Disk size VMWare provides an option to resize the Hard disk of a VM. The Settings dialog provides this option under Hard Disk. If the VM is not running and you don&amp;rsquo;t have a snapshot, the slider is enabled, and you can size the disk to your desired size.
I wanted to increase the size of the hard disk from 50 GB to 100 GB. That&amp;rsquo;s a matter of seconds, and I was ready to go.</description></item><item><title>TIL - SIGINFO is awesome</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-siginfo-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 09:15:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/til-siginfo-is-awesome/</guid><description>Today I learnt something really awesome. If you use a Unix based operating system, then you will be able to send any process a signal. This might be either Ctrl+C or SIGINT to interrupt that process. Or you can send SIGINFO to report the progress of it’s operation. Why this is awesome? Did you ever copy a huge amount of data and cp didn’t tell you how much has data has been copied so far?</description></item></channel></rss>