<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DIY on today is tomorrow's past</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/tags/diy/</link><description>Recent content in DIY on today is tomorrow's past</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</managingEditor><webMaster>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ingo-richter.io/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Update Prusa Mk3s Fan Shroud</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/update-prusa-mk3s-fan-shroud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/post/2022/update-prusa-mk3s-fan-shroud/</guid><description>A Better Fan Shroud I already updated my 3D Printer fan shroud a couple of months ago. It should cool the filament more effectively and evenly. I think it did a good job. Unfortunately, the shroud got too hot several times and was deformed. I was afraid that it now had reduced cooling performance. I found an update to the fan shroud that looked very efficient, and somebody analyzed the airflow, and it appeared to be very effective in cooling the filament.</description></item><item><title>Day350</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day350/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day350/</guid><description>WFH Day 350 It&amp;rsquo;s already the last day of a perfect month. Perfect in that sense that the month started with a Monday and ended adequately on a Sunday. :-)
I mentioned in my post that I was about to create my sourdough starter. It was an experiment, and I failed it. I assume that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the right place in my house with sufficient constant temperature (this house is so badly insulated :-|).</description></item><item><title>Day329</title><link>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><author>ingo@ingo-richter.io (Ingo Richter)</author><guid>https://ingo-richter.io/cv19wfh/2021/02/day329/</guid><description>WFH Day 329 A new year, and still, we are mostly trapped and confined in our homes without much todo. The days seem to follow the same pattern day in, day out. I went back to exercise more, not to feel brain tired, and have something accomplished with my body.
Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s not what I wanted to write. It was only something that came to my mind before I come to what I started two days ago: making a Sourdough starter.</description></item></channel></rss>